Contact

9008159212 (Mobile) debroyseshadri@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/seshadri-debroy (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Data Analysis

SQL

SAS Certified Base Programmer

Languages

Bengali (Native or Bilingual) English (Full Professional) Hindi (Full Professional)

Certifications

Coursera -Machine Learning sas certified base programmer for sas 9

Honors-Awards

school captain

Best project of the Quarter

First Nationwide BioTechnology Olympiad

Publications

Synthesis and Characterization of Al-4.5%Cu Alloy Powder Using Mechanical Alloying

Seshadri Deb Roy

Data Scientist.DXC Technology|| ISB CBA co'20 || B.Tech.NIT Rourkela || Ex- ABinBEV || Ex- Vedanta

Bengaluru

Summary

I am deeply interested and passionate about Machine Learning and AI deep learning. I have spent 6+ years in the Analytics and Data science industry with exposure to Retail and Banking Industry. I have a SAS Base certification backed by a degree from NIT Rourkela. With Initial years of experience in Business Analytics that has led me to pursue Advance Management Program in Business Analytics from Indian School of Business Hyderabad. I am seeking a profile as per my skill sets in a mid level position in an esteemed organization.

A Brief Profile summary:

Tools:

SAS Base and Advanced (Macros), Advanced MS Excel, Tableau, Power BI, Python Programming, R programming, SQL Programming.

Methodologies: Agile, DevOps

Data Visualization:

Tableau (Advanced Integrated features such as Rserve and TabPy)

Power BI

Python ML libraries (seasborn, ggplot and matplotlib)

Data Science Exposure:

Supervised Learning (Regression and Classification)

Unsupervised Learning: (Clustering and Segmentation, Dimensional

Reduction Techniques, Discriminant Analysis)

Recommendation System

Reinforcement Learning

Deep Learning Techniques: Neural Networks such as RNN, CNN and Multi Layer Perceptrons (MLP).

Time Series Forecasting Techniques:

Page 1 of 5

Moving Average Methods, Holt's method, Winter's Method and Holt Winter's Method.

Experience

DXC Technology
Data Scientist
January 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months)
Bengaluru Area, India

Anheuser-Busch InBev
Principal Analyst
October 2018 - January 2019 (4 months)
Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- The reports include despcriptive status of the PCR valuations and variance analysis in the YTD and LE values.
- Tools using R, Python, SAS BASE and Enterprise Guide and Power BI. Data Warehousing Using SAS and SQL to monitor the price change requests. EDA using Python and R to create multivariate analysis for the sales in different regions across NAZ.
- Tableau visualization in form of word cloud to see which brands are popular among the consumers.

Mapbox integration in tableau to figure out which region to focus in more which were recorded with least sales.

- I have worked on Cash forecast weekly reports. The Price change valuations for the products from the brewery to the wholesalers and then to the retailers were tracked through invoices. Based on the price valuations for each week, using Time series forecasting method we would arrive to the price change for the upcoming five weeks.
- Developed ETL on SAS enterprise guide. Created multiple jobs that used to be run on weekly and monthly basis. These jobs included promo offers for the products and military commission report as well.

Axis Bank

Business Analyst

June 2017 - October 2018 (1 year 5 months)

Mumbai Area, India

- Analysis of Credit Active customer Base and driving the targets set for the channel resources.
- Worked on dynamic dashboards with tableau integrated with Rserve and TabPy. Used a linear regression model on independent variables such as Credit, Debit and interest added amount to predict the change in expected account balance.
- I had performed on Channel dashboards as a part of monthly activities and related adhocs and datawarehousing using SAS Enterprise Guide.
- Credit Risk project carried out on the customer base provided from the various campaigns run of online channel to enhance the usage of bank products.
- The Forecasting of annual budget for FY18-19 using Holt's Winter's method using R. I carried out the project from beginning to end monitoring a team of 3 persons.
- Mastered the ability to design and deploy rich Graphic visualizations with Drill Down and Drop down menu option and Parameters using Tableau.
- Worked closely with Business users. Interacted with ETL developers, Project Managers, and members of the QA teams.
- Created different KPI using calculated key figures and parameters
- Developed Tableau data visualization using Cross tabs, Heat maps, Box and Whisker charts, Scatter Plots, Geographic Map, Pie Charts and Bar Charts and Density Chart.
- Developed donut charts and implemented complex features in charts like creating bar charts in tooltip.

TEG Analytics 2 years 2 months

Business Analyst

October 2015 - May 2017 (1 year 8 months)

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

I was part of a US based CPG client project which I worked upon as it is related to Retail and Consumer Goods domain. The project was on digital warehousing of data across the regions in United states. The client was aiming at planning for it's budget allocation for the upcoming Financial Year. The problem statement in here was to unearth insights from the digital data provided so that it study the current year performance across regions and then use those insights for budget allocation for digital marketing strategy through various online channels for the next year.

The Key metrics that were worked upon from the data were Clicks, Impression, Click Through Ratio (CTR), Bounce Rate, Cost Per Click, Impression Duration. To Further analyze the consumer behavior the other metrics worked upon were Consumer ID, Location, Transaction amount, Product ID, Product Category etc.

The conclusions were that most of the product that engaged consumers were from online channels and Paid Searches were the most effective among them Followed by Earned channels and then owned channels. In traditional Media TV was more effective then Print. The budget allocation for the next Financial Year was assigned with major portion to Online Channels and Furthermore into Paid searches.

The region wise segmentation concluded that the Spanish speaking population residing in the Southern states of U.S. were more in numbers as buyers hence the ads and impressions on TV were to be more in Spanish.

The shift from traditional to Online media helped in reducing the cost by 40%.

Data Analyst

April 2015 - October 2015 (7 months)

Bengaluru

I began with the CPG Retail Project and within 6 months I was promoted as Business Analyst.

Vedanta Resources Plc
Process Engineer
March 2013 - April 2014 (1 year 2 months)

Education

Indian School of Business

Advance Management Program in Business Analytics, Data Science · (2019 - 2020)

National Institute of Technology Rourkela B.Tech, Metallurgical and Materials Engineering · (2008 - 2012)

Central Board of Secondary Education Science - (PCM) · (2007 - 2008)

Central Board of Secondary Education (2005 - 2006)